brandonjimzz@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/brandon-jimenez https://brandon-jimenez.github.io/resume

## **IT System & Security Specialist**

An experienced IT professional with a passion for System Administration and Information Security with 4 years of experience in troubleshooting and supporting a variety of systems. Looking to bring my work experience and knowledge gained through certifications and self-study to a Cybersecurity Analyst role within your company.

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

PLATFORMS: Windows, Linux

TOOLS: Active Directory, Microsoft Office, Bomgar, ServiceNow, SSMS, SCCM, Security Onion

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, SQL, Python (Basic)

SKILLS: Building Secure Environments, Data Security, Security Policies, Threat Intelligence, Vulnerability

Management, Virtualization, Inventory Management, Network/System Troubleshooting

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- CompTIA Cybersecurity Analyst+ ce
- CompTIA Security+ ce
- CompTIA Network+ ce
- Dell EMC Proven Professional Associate: Information Storage and Management v3

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### **Kiewit Corporation**, Omaha, NE — Technology Group Senior Service Technician

October 2018 - PRESENT

Currently responsible for preparing and shipping PC's to Kiewit's end users based on information submitted through our internal ticket system. Focused primarily on the tactical elements of PC diagnostics, repair, and imaging.

- Project Management Lead for troubleshooting efficiencies, operations and maintenance
- Revitalized Knowledge Base for team distribution; Troubleshooting and Team Policies
- Auditing software logs to ensure documented guidelines for team process are in line within specifications; ensuring headache-free customer service experience
- Analyzing and addressing severe hardware issues
- Abiding to established processes for imaging and repairing computers
- Facilitating open collaboration with inter-departmental technology teams, optimizing customer experience
- Maintaining and tracking available PC inventory for a significant portion of the Kiewit Technology Group.

## Brandon Jimenez Omaha, NE (201)-878-2573

brandoniimzz@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/brandon-jimenez https://brandon-jimenez.github.io/resume

### First Data, Omaha, NE — Contact Center Technical Specialist

November 2017 - October 2018

While working for First Data (now Fiserv) I was responsible for performing routine merchant account-related transactions and was the main point of contact for issues with point of sale systems. During my tenure I was promoted to Web Portal Payment Support due to my technical proficiency and troubleshooting ability.

- Investigated and resolved a wide variety of technical issues and requests relating to point of sale systems
- Dynamically upheld PCI Compliance
- Managed inbound calls for software and POS systems
- Incident management; restoring services within agreed SLAs
- Disseminated complex information to tech users of all abilities

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Purdue University Global,** West Lafayette, IN - Bachelor of Science, Cybersecurity August 2021 - Current

- Became familiar with applying security principles and practices to maintain operations in the presence of risks and threats
- Learned to recognize professional responsibilities and make informed judgments in computing practice based on legal and ethical principles
- Became familiar with fundamentals of cybersecurity, recognizing best practices, and identifying IT security threats and products
- Learned to plan, implement, upgrade, or monitor security measures for the protection of computer networks and information

## **Metropolitan Community College,** Omaha, NE — Associate in Applied Science, Server Administration

November 2018

- Became familiar with implementing, configuring, and maintaining a Windows Server
- Became familiar with implementing and configuring Active Directory environments for organizations of all sizes
- Gained a strong technical foundation in monitoring and managing a network infrastructure
- Hands on experience setting up a virtualized environment (ESXi vSphere) and implementing enterprise server hardware within a data center

## Brandon Jimenez Omaha, NE (201)-878-2573

brandonjimzz@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/brandon-jimenez https://brandon-jimenez.github.io/resume

#### **PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT**

#### **Home Lab**

- Homebrew KB to document design and configuration
  - o MkDocs and Material for MkDocs on Docker
- Home automation services
  - o Homebridge to connect third party devices into Apple's HomeKit
- VMs for learning Windows Server, Ubuntu, Fedora and Kali Linux; virtual networking
  - o VMware Workstation Pro in conjunction with ESXi 6.5 & 6.7
- Penetration testing
  - Utilizing primarily Kali Linux to connect and interact with boxes on TryHackMe and HackTheBox
  - o Basic python script writing creating word lists & ping sweep